Guide to the Edith Kramer Papers MC.215
New York University Archives
Edith Kramer Papers
circa 1920-2010
New York University Archives
Kramer, Edith, 1916-2014
MC.215
15.75 Linear Feet In 52 custom portfolios, 6 oversize flat boxes, 4 manuscript boxes, 1 half manuscript box, 5 flat file folders, 6 record cartons, 14 large artworks, 1 card box, and two shared boxes.
Edith Kramer (1916-2014) was an Austrian artist, author, teacher, and art therapist. She emigrated to the United States in 1938 and in the following decades worked with children as an art teacher and art therapist in a variety of institutions. Kramer joined the faculty of New York University in 1973 in order to help develop an art therapy graduate program. The collection documents her academic career with her publications, lecture notes, and syllabi; her work as an art therapist with patient notes and artwork created by patients; and her career as a working artist with artworks created by Kramer throughout her life.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into 5 series. Series I is grouped by topic or document type and arranged chronologically within those groupings. Series II is organized by document type. Series III is organized by correspondent and document type. Series IV is organized by document type. Series V is arranged into two sub-series: Sub-Series V.A is grouped by medium and then arranged chronologically. Sub-Series V.B has not been arranged by an archivist.
Series I: Publications and Professional Papers, 1898-2005
Series II: Photographs and Slides
Series III: Personal Papers
Series IV: Audiovisual Materials
Series V: Artwork, 1937-2000
Sub-series V.A: Artwork by Edith Kramer, 1937-1993
Sub-series V.B: Artwork Created During Art Therapy, 1951-2000
Source of acquisition
The collection was donated to the University Archives by David Henley in 2011.
Scope and Contents
This collection reflects Edith Kramer's work as an artist, art therapist, and teacher. She began making art as a child and this collection includes artworks she created throughout her life. The majority of her artworks in the collection are pencil and ink drawings, but she worked in many media including sculpture, mosaic, collage, oil and watercolor paints, and printmaking, all of which are also represented in this collection. Kramer created mosaic murals for two New York City subway stations, Spring Street and Union Square, and this collection includes proposals and planning documents related to these two murals as well as proposals for others subway station murals that were never made. The collection also includes drawings of subway stations, trains, and riders. In addition to original artworks, there are slides and photographs of many of her pieces. The collection also includes files related to Friedl Dicker-Brandeis, Kramer's childhood art teacher and mentor; personal correspondence; and date books.
This collection documents Kramer's work as a practicing art therapist, most notably her work at Wiltwyck School for Boys, a residential treatment facility in Esopus, New York. Kramer's notes about patients at Wilkwyck, artwork created by these patients in the course of art therapy, and example artworks created by Kramer are all included, as are documents related to and drafts of her 1958 book, Art therapy in a children's community: a study of the function of art therapy in the treatment program of Wiltwyck School for Boys. Slides and photographs also document patient artwork.
Kramer's work as an academic is documented in scholarly publications, including journal articles and her 1971 book, Art as Therapy with Children. The collection also includes syllabi, lecture notes and recordings, and a program prospectus for the graduate program in art therapy at New York University.
Conditions Governing Access
Sketchbooks in box 19 contain personal health information (PHI) and are restricted. All other materials are open without restrictions. University Archives staff will review all requested material for PHI before providing access.
Biographical Note
Edith Kramer was born in 1916 in Vienna, Austria. At the age of 13, she began studying art under the tutelage of Friedl Dicker-Brandeis, an artist who worked within the Bauhaus movement. Dicker-Brandeis moved to Prague in 1934, and Kramer traveled there with her. While in Prague both women taught art to the children of families who had fled Nazi Germany. Kramer credited this formative experience with inspiring her interest in art therapy. Kramer grew up in a family with strong interests in Freudian psychoanalysis, and neo-Freudian concepts regarding attachment, aggression, and libidinal impulses later influenced her views on art therapy.
In 1938 Kramer fled Austria and arrived in New York City as a refugee. In 1938 she began teaching art and shop classes at the Little Red School House in Greenwich Village and she later went on to work in a machine shop during World War II.
In 1950 she was appointed art therapist at the Wiltwyck School for Boys in Esopus, New York. This appointment marked her first formal position as an art therapist. Her experiences at Wiltwyck inspired her seminal book, Art Therapy in a Children's Community, published in 1958. Over the next decades she made a name for herself as one of the pioneers of art therapy and worked to develop art therapy programs in a number of children's institutions including the Leak and Watts Children's Home, the Turtle Bay Music School, the Guild School of the Jewish Guild for the Blind, and the Albert Einstein College of Medicine, Department of Child Psychiatry. These experiences informed her 1971 work, Art Therapy with Children.
In 1971 Kramer was part of the team that founded an art therapy program at George Washington University. She then came to New York University in 1973 to create a graduate program in art therapy at the School of Education, Health, Nursing, and the Arts Professions (now the Steinhardt School of Culture, Education, and Human Development). By 1976, the program had obtained approval from the New York State Department of Education, and in 1979 it was one of the first programs to receive approval from the American Art Therapy Association.
Kramer was also an artist during her time in academia; she worked part-time as a professor and continued as a working artist. Kramer worked as a painter, sculptor, printmaker, mosaicist, and collage-maker and her works include landscapes, industrial paintings, sketches, etchings, and a number of sculptures. A mosaic she created for the Metropolitan Transit Authority may be found in the Spring Street A/C/E subway stop.
Kramer retired from NYU in 2005. She continued to lecture and make art until her death in 2014 at the age of 97.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Access CDs for audiovisual materials in the collection are available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only. Audiovisual materials that have not been preserved may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact University Archives, special.collections@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596 with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Custodial History
As of October, 2023 10 items are missing: 5 drawings by Edith Kramer and 5 artworks by her patients. Missing items are identified at the file level.
Research notes.; Psychotherapy.; Diaries; Photographs.; Emigration and immigration.; Painting.; Education.; World War, 1939-1945 -- Refugees.; Art -- Study and teaching.; Speeches.; Art therapy.; Notes.; Journals (periodicals); Drawings; Books.; Correspondence.; Subway stations.; Dicker-Brandeis, Friedl, 1898-1944; New York University -- History; Wiltwyck School for Boys (Esopus, N.Y.)
- Series I: Publications and Professional Papers, 1898-2005; 3.1 Linear Feet In 3 record cartons and one flat file folder.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains a number of publications, including numerous copies of Edith Kramer's 1958 book, Art therapy in a children's community: a study of the function of art therapy in the treatment program of Wiltwyck School for Boys, and her 1971 book, Art as Therapy with Children, in a variety of languages. It also includes the first 20 issues of the American Journal of Art Therapy, to which Edith Kramer often contributed. Also included in this series are papers on Friedl Dicker-Brandeis, CVs, lecture notes dating from Kramer's tenure at New York University, scholarly articles and book reviews in German and English, and a prospectus for the art therapy program at NYU. Kramer's professional impact is documented by tributes from colleagues. This series also includes a 1976 calendar displaying artwork by children who were patients at Bellevue Hospital.
  Arrangement
  Materials in this series are grouped by topic or publication title and arranged chronologically within those groupings. For example, all materials related to Art as Therapy with Children are grouped together and listed chronologically, as are all materials about Kramer's time as a professor at NYU.
  - Art Therapy Pamphlets (1), 1953-1977 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Art Therapy Pamphlets (2), 1966-1972 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Japanese Translation of Art as Therapy with Children by Edith Kramer, 1971 (Box 1, Object 3)
  - Japanese Translation of Art as Therapy with Children by Edith Kramer, 1971 (Box 1, Object 4)
  - Kunst als Therapie mit Kindern by Edith Kramer, 1975 (Box 1, Object 5)
  - Kunst als Therapie mit Kindern by Edith Kramer, 1975 (Box 1, Object 6)
  - Kunst als Therapie mit Kindern by Edith Kramer, 1997 (Box 1, Object 7)
  - Kunst als Therapie mit Kindern by Edith Kramer, 1997 (Box 1, Object 8)
  - Art Therapy in a Children's Community by Edith Kramer, 1977 (Box 1, Object 9)
  - Creativiteitstherapie met Kinderen by Edith Kramer, 1980 (Box 1, Object 10)
  - Chinese Translation of Art as Therapy with Children by Edith Kramer, 1993 (Box 1, Object 11)
  - Bornekunst i borneterapi by Edith Kramer, 1975 (Box 1, Object 12)
  - Bildterapi med barn by Edith Kramer, 1975 (Box 1, Object 13)
  - Kunst als Therapie mit Kindern by Edith Kramer, 2004 (Box 1, Object 14)
  - Art as Therapy by Edith Kramer, 2000 (Box 1, Object 15)
  - Kindheit und Kunsttherapire by Edith Kramer, 1998 (Box 1, Object 16)
  - Terapia a Traves del Arte en Una Comunidad Infantil by Edith Kramer, 1982 (Box 1, Object 17)
  - Edith Kramer: Malerin und Kunsttherapeutin Zwischen den Welten, 1997 (Box 1, Object 18)
  - Bulletin of Art Therapy, Volume 1, 1961 (Box 2, Object 1)
  - Bulletin of Art Therapy, Volume 2, 1962 (Box 2, Object 2)
  - Bulletin of Art Therapy, Volume 3, 1963 (Box 2, Object 3)
  - Bulletin of Art Therapy, Volume 4, 1964 (Box 2, Object 4)
  - Bulletin of Art Therapy, Volume 5, 1965 (Box 2, Object 5)
  - Bulletin of Art Therapy, Volume 6, 1966 (Box 2, Object 6)
  - Bulletin of Art Therapy, Volume 7, 1967 (Box 2, Object 7)
  - Bulletin of Art Therapy, Volume 8, 1968 (Box 2, Object 8)
  - American Journal of Art Therapy, Volume 9, 1969 (Box 2, Object 9)
  - American Journal of Art Therapy, Volume 10, 1970 (Box 2, Object 10)
  - American Journal of Art Therapy, Volume 11, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Object 11)
  - American Journal of Art Therapy, Volume 12, 1972 (Box 2, Object 12)
  - American Journal of Art Therapy, Volume 13, 1973 (Box 2, Object 13)
  - American Journal of Art Therapy, Volume 14, 1974 (Box 2, Object 14)
  - American Journal of Art Therapy, Volume 15, 1975 (Box 2, Object 15)
  - American Journal of Art Therapy, Volume 16, 1976 (Box 2, Object 16)
  - American Journal of Art Therapy, Volume 17, 1977 (Box 2, Object 17)
  - American Journal of Art Therapy, Volume 18, 1978 (Box 2, Object 18)
  - American Journal of Art Therapy, Volume 19, 1979 (Box 2, Object 19)
  - American Journal of Art Therapy, Volume 20, 1980 (Box 2, Object 20)
  - Transcripts in German (1), Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Transcripts in German (2), Undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Transcripts in German (3), Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Article on Austria's Contributions to Art Therapy, Undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Translation from Meister Floh, Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Art as Therapy - Collected Papers Manuscript Draft, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Art as Therapy - Collected Papers Manuscript Original, Undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Original Articles from Journals, 1992-2001 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Deutsm - German Articles, Undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Current State of Knowledge in the Area of this Proposal by Edith Kramer, Undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Madi Eulogy by Edith Kramer, Undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Wiltwyck: Art and the Troubled Child, Undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Cards from Wiltwyck School, Undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Transcripts on Aggression, Undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Gallery Programs, 1993-1997 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Edith Kramer Bilder 1980-1990 Program, August 31- October 6, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Edith Kramer & Luise A. Rudeloff: Wirklichkeit & Kunst, 1991 March-April (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Lo Contemporaneo Y lo Atemporal en Nueva York - Gallery Review, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Tribute Panel Remarks - David Henley, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Tribute to Edith Kramer - Judy Rubin, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Tribute to Edith Kramer - Lam Gerity, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Tribute to Edith Kramer - Anni Brgman, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Tribute to Edith Kramer - Laurie Wilson, 2005 December 3 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Edith Kramer Tribute Poster, 2005 (Flat-file-folder 9)
  - A Memorial Celebration: Viola M. Bernard, 1998 May 19 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Tribute to Edith Kramer - Martha Haesler, 2005 December 3 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Friedl Dicker Brandeis Documents (1), 1898-1944 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Friedl Dicker Brandeis Documents (2), 1898-1988 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - From Bauhaus to Terezin poster, 1989 (Flat-file-folder 9)
  - Art Therapy Report, 1951-1965 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Art Therapy Report, 1951-1956 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Art Therapy Report, 1950-1955 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Art Therapy Report, 1959-1960 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Vitae, Undated (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Book Reviews, 1972-1980 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Pictures of Animals Painting, Undated (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Certificates/Awards, 1984-2001 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Unfinished Edith Kramer Articles, Undated (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Articles by David Henley, 1988-2004 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Documents Concerning Wiltwyck Art Therapy Book, 1950-1957 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Collected Postcards, Undated (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Resource Materials, Undated (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Postcards and Christmas Cards, Undated (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - German Articles/Reviews, 1971-2001 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Manuscript on Art for Elizabeth - Corrections, Undated (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - NYU Lecture Notes 1, 1973, Undated (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - NYU Lecture Notes 2, 1973, Undated (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - NYU Syllabi, 1999-2002 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Clippings, 1985-2003 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - The Mosaic Manuscript, 1992-1994 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Kramer - Perception Edits, Undated (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Handwritten Keynote Speech Art Therapy Association, Undated (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Workshop in Art Therapy & Bibliography, Undated (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - On the Ethology of Human Aggression - Lecture for 1997 AATA Conference (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Short Perspective Manuscript, Undated (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Master of Arts in Art Therapy Prospectus, 1995-04 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Informative Media Receipt for Edith Kramer's Course on PsychoDynamic Process Edits, 2003 April 12 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Calendar by the children of Bellevue Hospital Center, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Three Art Therapists -- poster, undated (Flat-file-folder 9)
- Series II: Photographs and Slides, 2.5 Linear Feet In 2 record cartons and one manuscript box.
  Scope and contents
  This series contains slides and photographs. Some slides were labeled by the donor, and where it was possible, the original label was retained and put in quotation marks. The majority of slides are of Edith Kramer's adolescent patients' artwork, sometimes organized by patient, by institution, or by psychotherapy principle. A good portion of the slides are also of Edith Kramer's own work, ranging from late 1930s paintings to works completed as recently as 2001. The photographs mainly comprise pictures of Edith Kramer, pictures and prints of her artwork, and photographs of her young patients' artwork. Also included are examples of artworks created by other art therapists or their patients that were given to Kramer.
  The photographs and slides are organized roughly by format. Slides are arranged in sleeves as they were received from the donor; when slides were rehoused, this arrangement was preserved.
  - Patient Sculpture Slides, 1964-1966 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Patient Artwork Slides, Undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Patient Artwork Slides, Undated, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Patient Artwork Slides, 1964-1967, Undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Transference" & "Degraded Self Slides, 1962-1969, Undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Patient Artwork Slides, 1966-1969, Undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Patient Artwork Slides, 1957-1969, Undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Patient Artwork Slides, 1964-1966, Undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Patient Artwork Slides, 1964-1966, Undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Circles Patient Artwork Slides, 1969, Undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Masks and Monsters Artwork Slides, Undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - 9W 78 Patient Artwork Slides, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Onion Sorting Onion Fields Edith Kramer Portraits, 1986, Undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Luz Feoern Edith Kramer Portraits, Undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Einsidelei, Undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous Jacoby, 1964-1966 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Adult Amateurs, Undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Pathology NYU 75/76 Slides, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Blind Slides of Blind Child Carliss's Sculpture, 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Iris Patient Artwork Slides, 1965-1969, Undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Retarded Patient Artwork Slides, 1977-1990, Undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Aggression Patient Artwork Slides, 1965-1969, Undated (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - II Patient Artwork, Undated (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Misc. Timmi Edith Kramer Artwork Slides, 1981-1991, Undated (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - David Austracia Edith Kramer Artwork Slides, 1953-1997, Undated (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Friedl Artwork Slides, Undated (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Pat Workman Artwork Slides, 1983, Undated (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - 80s Still Life Artwork Slides, 1960-1983, Undated (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - At Horrors Artwork Slides, Undated (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Howard Artwork Slides, 1969, Undated (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Evaluation Patient Artwork Slides, 1975, Undated (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Late 80s and Early 90s Artwork Slides, Undated (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Wiltwyck Patient Artwork Slides, 1967-1968, Undated (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Gabe & Angel Patient Artwork Slides, 1964-1966, Undated (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Development Patient Artwork Slides, 1964-1965, Undated (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Edith Kramer's Artwork/Making of Subway Mosaic Slides, 1945-1994, Undated (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Edith Kramer Artwork Slides, 1944-1996, Undated (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Edith Kramer Artwork Slides, 1944-1997, Undated (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Edith Kramer Artwork, 1938, 1999, Undated (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Unidentified Artwork, Undated (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - New York Portrait Slides, 1968-1987, Undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Allan Artwork Slides, 1973, Undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Sculpture Slides, 1965 November -December (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Edith Kramer Artwork Slides, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - L&W Artwork Slides, 1959-1962, Undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Early Grundlsee Artwork Slides, 1968-1994, Undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Vera Artwork Slides, 1984, Undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Bronwen Artwork Slides, 1977, Undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Edith Kramer Artwork, 1934-1938 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Grundlsee Slides, 2001-2002 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Melvin Aggression Slides, 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Carmine & Vera Artwork Slides, Undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Chi Artwork Slides, 1959-1962 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Edith Kramer's Artwork Slides, 1994 February (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Greek and Medieval Artwork, 1984-1989, Undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Dough Edith Kramer Artwork Slides, Undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Color Patient Artwork Slides, 1965-1978, Undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Larry Patient Artwork Slides, 1967, Undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Samantha Artwork Slides, 1971, Undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Friedl's Students' Artwork, Undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Edith Kramer's Drawings, 1944-1947 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Anal Patient Artwork Slides, Undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Edith Kramer Artwork Slides, 1966-1990, Undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Demonstration I Patient Artwork Slides, 1971, Undated (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Poco Paintings of the Outdoors Slides, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Messers Good and Evil/ Messer Schmidt Slides, Undated (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Disturbed Body Image/ Degraded Self Patient Artwork Slides, Undated (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Sublimination & Pre Patient Artwork Slides, 1965-1966, Undated (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - I Patient Artwork Slides, Undated (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Third Hand Patient Artwork Slides, Undated (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Edith Kramer Artwork Slides, 1987-1998 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Relief & Egg Temren Artwork Slides, Undated (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Girl's Horses Patient Artwork Slides, 1965-1966, Undated (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Chi Larry et al Patient Artwork Slides, 1969, Undated (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Michael WWyck Patient Artwork Slides, 1950-1952 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Hersch Spring '87 Sculpture Slides, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Carlissa Patient Artwork Slides, 1972 December (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Carliss Nude Sculpture Slides, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Jacoby Patient Artwork Slides, 1966, Undated (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Adolescent and Pre L&W Patient Artwork Slides, Undated (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Borderline Evaluations Patient Artwork Slides, Undated (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Edith Kramer Artwork Slides, 1968-1997, Undated (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Linda & Judy Patient Artwork Slides, Undated (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Early '86 & Still Life Edith Kramer Artwork Slides, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - At Horrors Patient Artwork Slides, Undated (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Charles Patient Artwork Slides, Undated (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - 80s & Norway Edith Kramer Artwork Slides, Undated (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Rickers Artwork Slides, Undated (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Subway Sculptures and Paintings Edith Kramer Artwork Slides, 1985-1992, Undated (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Brooklyn Beach Edith Kramer Artwork, 1971, Undated (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Timmi Patient Artwork Slides, Undated (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Gabe Patient Artwork Slides, 1964-1965, Undated (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Larry, Ken, Stuart, Anthony Patient Artwork Slides, 1966 February (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Juanita, Domaseo, Antony, Mark, Howie Patient Artwork Slides, 1966 March (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Jacob, Carlos, Transference Patient Artwork Slides, 1969-1970, Undated (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - [Redacted] Patient Artwork Slides, 1970, Undated (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Sculpture Patient Artwork Slides, 1963-1966, Undated (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Evaluation Patient Artwork Slides, 1975-1978, Undated (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Gabe & Companions Patient Artwork Slides, 1963-1969 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Monster Faces Patient Artwork Slides, Undated (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - Late 70s- Early 80s Edith Kramer Artwork Slides, 1975, Undated (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - Edith Kramer Artwork Slides, 1998-2000 (Box 5, Folder 62)